In the very beginning of the lesson you have already seen this diagram.
レッスンの最初で既にこの図をご覧いただいてると思います
By now you might be able to guess why the Behavior Module
今では トラジェクトリーモジュールなどに比べて動作モジュールがあまり更新されない理由が
updates on a lower frequency than for example the Trajectory Module.
お分かりいただけるかもしれません
This is due to the fact that the high level decisions made in
これは ハイレベルな決定を動作モジュールで行い もっと時間がかかり
the behavior module spend a longer time horizon and just don't change as frequently.
頻繁に変更しないことが理由です
But the Trajectory Module does still count on
しかしトラジェクトリーモジュールは未だ私たちの決定を頼りにしており
our decisions and it's important that the over all system architecture
動作プランナーなどの比較的遅いモジュールが
doesn't allow for a comparatively slow module like
他のより速いコンポーネントの適切な機能を詰まらせることを
the behavior planner to clog up the proper functioning of the other faster components.
システムアーキテクチャ全体が考慮していないことが問題です
Let's take a second to talk about what's known as
問題のスケジューリングとして知っていること 自動運転車では
a scheduling problem and how it can be handled in the self-driving car.
どのように取り扱われるかについてお話ししましょう
This diagram shows what happens during two processing cycles of the Behavior Module.
この図では 動作モジュールの 2 つの処理サイクル中に何が起こるのかを示しています
As you can see, the Prediction Module updates with a higher frequency than Behavior.
見てお分かりのとおり 予測モジュールは動作モジュールに比べ 高頻度で更新されます
Trajectory is even higher. And so on.
トラジェクトリーモジュールはそれ以上ですといった具合にです
But focus your attention on what happens after behavior has completed its first cycle.
でも 動作がその最初のサイクルを完了したあと 何が起こるのかに注目してください
To begin its second cycle,
その 2 番目のサイクルを開始するには
the behavior module needs data from prediction and localization.
動作モジュールは予測およびローカライゼーションからデータが必要です
For localization, it's easy in theory since at
ローカライゼーションの場合 この例では 新しいデータがあり
this instant it will have some fresh data and behavior could just use that.
動作はそれだけを使えるので 理論上では簡単です
But what about for prediction.
でも 予測の場合はどうでしょう
It's actually right in the middle of an update cycle at this instant.
この例では それは実際更新サイクル中です
Should behavior just wait until prediction is done?
動作は予測が完了するまで待っているべきでしょうか?
No. If we start waiting then we block up the pipeline for downstream components.
いいえ 待ち始めると 終了しているコンポーネントのパイプラインを遮断してしまいます
The answer is to use data from here and accept that it's a little stale.
答えは ここからデータを使用して少し古くなってしまうことを許容するです
When you implement your path planner for the final project,
最後のプロジェクトのハーフプランナーを実装するとき
we will provide you with the code that handles all of this.
このすべてを扱うコードを提供します
But it's worth mentioning that this is how it's done.
でも どのように行われるか説明することに越したことはありません